so we can measure performance as either
latency or throughput let's say now how
do we compare performance of two
different systems so we want to be able
to say something like system X is n
times faster than system Y and the way
we usually refer to this statement is
that the speed up of X over Y is equal
to n so we compute n as the speed of X
divided by speed of Y and now it starts
to matter whether we have latency as a
measure of speed or throughput for
throughput and can be computed simply as
the throughput of x divided by
throughput of Y but for latency speed of
X is not proportional to the latency of
X the longer the latency the lower the
speed so what we do instead is we divide
the latency of Y by the latency of X to
get the speed-up of x over Y